

PORTFOLIO
WWW.PAULGARROD.DEV

#### CONTACT

Mobile: 021 299 6363

Email: paulrgarrod@gmail.com Portfolio: www.paulgarrod.dev

LinkedIn: in/paulgarrod Address: Wellington, NZ Working Rights: NZ Resident

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

HTML, CSS & Bootstrap
JavaScript & Jquery
Node.JS, ExpressJS & NPM
Mongo BD
WordPress
GitHub
GOORM IDE & VS Code
Chrome Developer Tools

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Problem Solving
Communication
Time Management
Multi Tasking
Critical Thinking
Decision Making
Team Work
Leadership

#### **OTHER INTERESTS**

I love to experience different cultures and foods while scuba diving my way around the world!

Slowly learning Mandarin.

# **PAUL GARROD**

#### WEB DEVELOPER

As a self taught web developer, I'm a tenacious self starter.

Dedicated to the delivery of mobile first and fully responsive websites through continued learning and personal growth. I've conceived, created and deployed multiple projects, I'm currently working on a local business website upgrade and seeking a permanent position as a web developer.

Previous to Web Development, I've successfully managed businesses in the UK, Australia and New Zealand. I also taught Scuba Diving in Asia for 3+ years during a career break.

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# Full Stack Web Developer 2020 www.paulgarrod.dev

- Created multiple websites from concept through to deployment.
- Standardized mobile-first and fully responsive design layout.
- Simple UI/ UX design to enhance usability on mobile.
- Single page sites built with a back-end ready for expansion.
- Travel Information site which supplements a Facebook Group.
- Movie Database Search engine.

# Web Developer Bootcamp 2020

The Bootcamp culminated in a fully functioning Classifieds web application. Which was built using the following technologies/methods.

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap & Semantic UI
- Javascript, Node.js, ExpressJS, NPM, API calls
- Mongo DB
- RESTFUL Routing & CRUD Operations
- Authentification & Authorizations
- Built in the GOORM IDE, hosted on Heroku with GitHub version control

# **Business Manager 2012 - Present**

United Kingdom, Australia, New Zealand. 2012 - 2020

- Managing and operating multi-million dollar hospitality businesses.
- Leading teams of up to 40 staff, and 4-6 Managers.
- Mentored and coached staff & managers throughout development.
- Managed Award Winning Venues in the UK and Australia.

## **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science (Hons) in Psychology

University of Lincoln, England, UK. 2006 - 2009